[♪ sinister music playing]
[creature gurgling]
[pants]
-[Slightly] Arthur.
-[creature snores]
I thought maybe you were hungry.
[Arthur breathing heavily]
[Slightly sniffles]
-[creature gurgling]
-Sorry, sorry. Sorry, sorry, sorry.
Sorry.
-[creature gurgles]
-[Slightly exclaims]
-[Slightly gasps]
-[Arthur chokes]
[knocks on door]
[Smee whispering] Hey!
Hey, I hear you. I know you're in there.
G… Go away, I'm busy!
What are you… What are you talking about?
We're never busy.
[groans]
[knocking on door]
Shh. Shh. Shh. Keep your voice down!
[Smee] You're being a shit.
-[knocking on door]
-[Slightly] Please leave me alone, Smee.
Leave me alone. Please!
-Somebody's gonna hear you, Smee.
-[Smee] I don't-- Okay, I don't care.
-Let me in. I know something's going on.
-[Slightly] You're gonna ruin everything.
What are you talking about?
-What?
-No. It's… Can I… Can…
-Is somebody hiding?
-[creature gurgling]
Is… It's-It's a per… It's a person.
What did you do?
[screams, panting]
Slightly!
Slightly.
Slightly… what… what… Hey, hey.
[Slightly] You can't tell anybody.
Okay? Do you promise?
'Cause if you do, that man from the ship,
he's gonna kill my family.
Y-You did this to Arthur?
You…
You would have too if he had chosen you.
Blackmail or whatever you call it.
Dead mother, dead brothers, dead everyone.
Is he gonna be okay?
Like, it's not--
It's-It's not gonna kill him?
-No.
-[Smee] Great.
That's-That's-That's what the man said.
He said he just needs the monster.
Once he has it, he'll let Arthur go.
Okay?
I just… I just-just… I just need
to get him out of here.
This is, uh…
-To where?
-To the beach.
Have to get him to the beach.
Okay.
Smee.
Will you help me?
-Please.
-No.
-Please!
Please.
Okay.
-[Slightly] You will?
-Yeah.
[Slightly] Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
Please, grab his legs.
Grab his legs!
Come on, Smee.
[pants] Just grab his legs.
[chattering on radio]
[Smee] Slightly,
corridor's empty. Let's go.
[alarm blaring]
[electricity hums, crackles]
[clicks]
[alarm stops, chimes]
[guard 1] Clear.
[electricity crackling]
[guard 2] Clear, sir.
Collect the hybrid.
Put the fly back in its cage.
Yes, sir.
[sighs]
You should be safe for now.
Okay. What did we lose?
One of the children got careless.
Oh. Really, which one?
I'll send him to bed without any supper.
That one.
Is that…
Isaac.
Tootles.
The fly did this?
Yes. They digest their food
outside their bodies.
Organic matter must have been scarce in
their world, so they eat mostly minerals.
Amazing.
Where are we on reboot and restore?
Conceptually, it's possible.
Practically, we haven't cracked it.
There goes that six billion.
-No more kids in the lab.
-Except Wendy.
Yeah, of course,
but you need to watch her,
-make sure there are no more accidents.
-This wasn't an accident, Isaac's death.
-You just said…
-You need to watch the tape.
[grunts]
[scoffs] The calculation.
Knowing the consequences of his actions.
Most animals know
cause and effect to some degree.
[Boy Kavalier] Yeah, but the sheep
didn't benefit directly from his action,
the fly did.
So, why do it?
I want him moved.
-Precaution?
-Yeah, something like that.
What's going on?
Is…
What is that?
An accident.
Yeah, horrible.
Couldn't be avoided,
but it's… it's all contained now.
"Contained." What happened?
Wh-What happened to Isaac?
Science.
No, we… we can't. We're premium.
Don't.
I've got to tell the others.
Hol… Hold on there.
Let's think this through a minute.
We don't wanna scare everyone, right?
You know, a freak accident like this.
You know what kids are like
if they get an idea in their head.
"Oh, my God, we're not safe." [chuckles]
And suddenly there's no talking to them.
We're not safe?
N… No, no, that's not what…
Talk to her.
[Wendy] Please get out of my way. [pants]
[Wendy screeching]
You can't just erase things.
Oh, shit. Where are the others?
We've got to get to them before her.
[punching keys]
[beeps]
-I don't know.
-What do you mean, you don't know?
Someone turned their trackers off.
Fuck!
[smacks table]
Marcy.
Marce.
He's dead.
[Hermit] What?
Isaac's dead.
They said it was an accident.
I am so sorry.
We're not safe here. We have to go.
-We can't. They track us.
-[Hermit] No, not anymore.
Arthur.
All of us?
[Hermit] All of you.
We have to get everybody.
I don't know how much time we have
until they realize that something's wrong.
We can't collect everyone.
-I can't leave without…
-Marcy, we have to.
Would you leave without me?
No, of course not.
Because you're my brother.
Right.
Then you get why I have to try.
Okay.
But fast.
Nibs?
What did you say to her?
[Wendy] The truth, that's all.
No, you freaked her out.
Well, she should be freaked out.
We should all be freaked out.
You know what they did to her.
Yeah, they tried to help,
and you ruined it.
-They erased her memories.
-[Nibs] No.
I've got all my mind.
What's in me.
Nobody's messing with my insides.
Isn't that right, Mr. Strawberry?
What's ours is ours
and nobody can take it.
Isaac's dead.
We're not safe here.
I don't think we ever were.
We were fine
until you made us get your brother.
-It's not his fault!
-[Curly] No, I know that.
It's yours.
The boy genius is not your friend.
-He owns us.
-Don't talk about him like you understand.
He just wants to help people
like he helped us.
[Nibs sniffles] We're all gonna die here.
And then the bugs will crawl in,
and we'll all be ghosts.
Nibs…
I don't want to be a ghost.
Okay, we have to go.
This is the best place I've ever been.
Promise me,
really promise you won't tell on us.
Promise me, Curly.
I promise.
[Hermit] Marcy.
[chattering on radio]
-[door closes]
-[Hermit] We gotta go, Marcy.
What are you doing?
-[door opens]
-[alarm blaring]
[alien screeching]
[Wendy] Come on, Nibs.
What did you do?
[door opens]
[Boy Kavalier] Where is he?
-Who?
-[Boy Kavalier] The spouse.
You fired him. He's on a transport.
No, he isn't. He didn't get on the plane.
What he did do was turn off
all their trackers. Was that the plan?
Turn off their trackers
and smuggle my kids off the island?
-He wouldn't.
-Why? Because he's a fucking saint?
[Kirsh] The footage confirms it.
Arthur and the brother turned off
the trackers a couple of hours ago.
[Boy Kavalier] So you tell me
how you don't know anything about this.
I don't.
[alarm blaring]
[computer] Secure lab breach.
Secure lab breach.
[Boy Kavalier] Be useful.
[computer] Secure lab breach.
Yes, sir.
Secure lab breach.
[screaming]
[chattering on radio]
[Slightly, Smee panting]
-Okay.
-[Smee] Wait, wait, wait.
-[Slightly] Okay. This way.
-[Smee] Wait, no. Slightly!
Slightly, stay, stay.
-Yeah.
-[door opens]
What are you doing?
[Slightly] Um…
[Kirsh] Well?
[Slightly] The man from the ship.
He's been… He's been talking
to me in my head.
He asked me to bring Arthur to the beach.
I know that.
[exhales]
I mean, what are you doing going that way?
The quickest way to the beach
is to take the secure elevator.
-[clicks]
-[elevator beeps]
You're gonna be late.
B7.
That's my name.
Rose Ellis.
What I was called before.
It's not us.
We're still here.
I don't think I am anymore.
-[twig breaking]
-[chattering on radio]
[Hermit] We have to go.
[Smee] Why do you think
Kirsh didn't get us in trouble?
[Slightly] I don't know. It's…
-Oh, shit!
-[twigs breaking]
[Slightly] Hide.
[both panting]
[chattering on radio]
-Let's go.
-Wait, wait, wait.
They're gone.
Wait. Wait.
Uh-oh.
Where… Where did we… Where did we put it?
-It was… It was right here.
-Arthur.
[Smee] No, no, no, no.
-[Slightly] Arthur. Arthur.
-[Smee] Arthur! No.
-No, no, no, no.
-Arthur.
[Slightly] Arthur.
I can't find him.
[both screaming]
-[Smee screaming] Oh, my God! Get it!
-[Slightly screaming]
[person] Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, wait.
What is that?
[Slightly] Uh…
Where are we?
There was… There was a problem,
and we had to evacuate.
A problem?
Your wife's waiting for us
down at the beach.
There was… It was just…
There-There was some kind of…
[Slightly] "Contanimation."
Yeah, contamination.
[Slightly] Yeah.
Yeah, and then we had… we had to evacuate.
So, then we… we carried you.
You had to carry me?
W-Why? Did something happen?
You don't remember?
I remember Tootles
was missing, and… Hmm…
-[Smee] Oh. The gas leak.
-[Slightly] Right.
-The gas leak.
-Yeah.
-Yeah, and then you breathed it.
Yeah, like…
And then
everyone went out ahead of us, and…
now they're waiting for us at the beach.
Confusion is a side effect of the gas.
We'll help you.
-[Arthur] Yeah, okay.
-Yeah.
-Okay?
-[Arthur] Yeah.
We had a… we had a fight,
me and my Dame,
and then I was supposed to…
I-I have to leave for a while.
I don't want her last memory of me to be…
I hope…
I'm sorry.
-Thank you.
-Oh.
I… I think you maybe saved my life.
You're welcome.
Yeah, we should go.
-Yeah, we should go.
-[Arthur] Yeah.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
-[waves crashing]
-[breathing heavily]
[screaming]
[groaning, choking]
-Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
-[Slightly] What?
We're almost there.
It's, uh… This is wrong.
[Smee] What?
No, man. It…
-Look, she-she's just over there.
-Yeah.
-No, no. [stutters] I-I don't… I-I…
-[Smee] She's just up there.
Whatever it is, you don't have to do it.
Now, we need to go back
and we figure it out together.
No, we're-we're just taking you
to your wife.
[Arthur] Yeah.
The thing is,
children have to learn how to lie.
And you two are still learning.
I-I don't know what's going on,
but I… I can tell you two are… are scared.
I'm not scared.
Now, see, that's the thing about lying.
You-You do it once
and you gotta keep on lying.
And you-you're lying to me
because you don't think I'll understand,
but the thing is, you know,
us who-who love you, we will understand.
So we're gonna… we're gonna go back…
you're gonna tell me what's going on,
and I promise you I'll help.
Okay?
Okay.
Slightly.
[Slightly] Yeah.
It's gonna be okay.
-[chokes]
-Whoa.
-Oh, God. Oh, G… Oh, G…
-What's happening, sir?
-[gasping]
-What's--
-[Slightly stutters]
-Wh… whoa…
-What's wrong with him? Arthur.
-Help! [screams]
-Arthur, Arthur.
-[Arthur screaming]
-[Smee] What do we do?
-What's happening?
Hey, Arthur. Arthur, Arthur.
-Let's get him up.
-Wait, wait!
-What do we do?
-Just help me get him up.
Oh, my God!
-[Smee] No, no.
-[alien screeches]
-[Slightly] What's happening?
-[Arthur screams]
What's happ… What's happ…
[Arthur, Smee screaming]
-[alien screeches]
-[Sightly, Smee screaming] Oh, my God!
What…
[Slightly, Smee panting]
[Slightly] Where'd it go? Where'd it go?
Where'd it go? Where'd it go?
-Please…
-[panting] Where'd it go? Where'd it go?
Smee, where'd it go? No, no, no, no.
That's the monster. They want it, Smee.
You said that he was gonna…
that he was gonna be okay.
-We…
-He wanted that… He… What did you do?
[Smee panting] You lied to me.
Look, I-I-I only said I was gonna help you
because you said
that he was gonna be okay.
[cries] No! No! Arthur.
Arthur? Arthur? Arthur, please!
Please! Slightly! Slightly! No.
Wait. Stop.
Slightly, please, ple… [breathing heavily]
-[Slightly grunting]
-What?
Slightly!
-What are you doing?
-[Slightly] We're going to be late!
Help me please, Smee!
Darling.
What is it?
Come here.
[Curly sniffles] Mother.
-What's wrong?
-[sniffles]
What's wrong?
Mom?
[sniffles, breathing shakily]
I'm here.
[sniffles]
Everything's hard
and I don't know what to do.
Shh.
You'll be okay, darling.
It'll be okay.
[sighs] I promise.
[Morrow] Landfall. Over.
Copy that. Team two. Landfall. Over.
[Morrow] Copy. Infiltrate. Stay low.
Shoot to kill. Over.
[soldier] Copy that. Over.
I told you to come alone.
I needed help. [pants]
He's my best friend, you can't hurt him.
Where is it?
I tried. I swear, I tried.
I did everything you asked me to.
If that were true, I wouldn't
be standing over a hollow corpse.
[Slightly] You don't understand.
Everything went wrong.
I did what you said.
I took him near the egg,
and the monster wrapped around his face.
But then, I-I don't know.
You didn't tell me that
there was going to be another monster.
And you-you said I had more time and…
[cries] …everything happened so fast--
-Stop talking.
-I swear.
Stop it.
You're acting like a child.
Do you know what grown-ups do
when they make a mistake?
They own up to it.
What about my mom? [breathing heavily]
You're not gonna hurt her, are you?
Bring them.
Please, please tell me.
What about my mom, huh?
Are you-Are you going to…
Please. Let go. Please.
Target one failed.
-[Slightly] Okay. Sorry. All right.
-Moving to target two.
[♪ dramatic music playing]
[Atom Eins] The xenomorph
exited the facility through a waste pipe.
No sign of Wendy or the Lost Boys.
This is not a good idea.
You're being ridiculous.
The more we move the specimens,
the more spread out they are,
the less we can guarantee containment.
You saw the footage, okay? This-This thing
orchestrated the incident with Tootles.
It's smart.
And I want to talk to it.
[speaking Spanish]
[speaking Japanese]
[speaking German]
[in English] Can you hear me?
Pen.
[sniffles]
We call this pi.
Yeah, it's the ratio of a circle's
circumference to its diameter.
All advanced civilizations
would know this figure.
So… what are the next three numbers?
[gurgling]
And?
[stomps]
And the next number?
[squelches]
[creature screaming]
-Sir, I must renew my concerns.
-[chuckles]
-Oh, my God.
-[screaming stops]
Oh, my God.
Oh. If only you could talk.
If this creature were to escape
and embed itself in the human population--
Or just one person.
-[Atom Eins] Sir?
-I'm saying you're right.
We should… Yeah,
we should switch it into a person.
You know,
someone who talks and uses a toilet.
One of the scientists maybe?
No, a mold scrubber, you know?
Someone with a low IQ,
so that we can see the difference.
Very good, sir.
I'll start a list.
No, no. Wait, wait. [chuckles]
I know just who to use.
[Hermit] We've got about a quarter mile
and there's a boat dock.
Arthur gave me the code.
-Okay.
-[Hermit] What?
-Shh.
[soldier] Easy. Bad idea.
Throw it on the ground.
You should go.
Before it's too late.
[soldier] Secure them.
We'll figure out
which ones are synths later.
[hisses]
Leave.
-Marcy, no.
-Now.
Or what?
[distant rumbling]
[soldier 2] What the fuck is that?
[screeching]
[twigs breaking]
[soldier 2] The fuck is that?
[soldiers screaming, groaning]
[alien screeching]
[chuckles]
-[creature purring]
-You let it out.
Stop, stop, stop. Joe, stop.
It's okay.
[chuckles]
[screeching]
[Hermit] What did you say to it?
Hide and follow.
I think.
Come on.
[Wendy] Let's go.
-[trap clangs]
-[creature screeches]
What did you do?
[creature screeching]
Drop your weapons.
Nobody likes a sore loser.
Finders keepers.
Boys, get over here.
This isn't over.
Nothing ever is.
Lock them up.
You two are grounded.
Untie us.
I'll start the motor.
-[Siberian] Told you he'd be here.
-[Rashidi] Whoa, whoa. Hey, chill, man.
We're just here to talk.
-Put your guns down.
-Hermit, what did I tell you?
I told you not to do this.
Now look where we are.
We have to go. Please.
-[Rashidi] Can't do it, man.
-[Hamm] Hands on your head.
Don't shoot. You'll hurt the merchandise.
My orders are to take you back.
-[soldier] Don't shoot.
-[Nagg] You fucked up, kid.
Mr. Strawberry says, "Fuck off."
We're never going back.
[Nagg] Off the boat. Now.
I see you.
[screams]
No!
[all grunting]
[grunts]
[Wendy screeching]
[Hermit] No. No.
[gunshots]
Oh, my God!
[grunting]
[grunts]
[electricity crackles]
No!
Drop it!
What did you do?
-[♪ "Song For The Dead" playing]
-[Rashidi] Drop it!
[sighs]
What did you do?
♪ It's late enough to go drivin' ♪
♪ And see what's mine ♪
♪ Life's the study of dyin' ♪
♪ How to do it right ♪
♪ You're a holy roller ♪
♪ If you're bettin' to lose ♪
♪ If you're hangin' around ♪
♪ I'm holdin' the noose ♪
[song ends]